A Guide to the Papers of Anne Spencer and the Spencer Family, 1829, 1864-2007
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Photographs (Box-folder 7:1-9:9)
  - n.d. Photograph - Rawley Martin Long (Box-folder 7:36))
  - 1944, n.d. Photograph - Joe Louis, boxer (Box-folder 7:37))
  - 1930 Photograph - Lynchburg, Virginia, Post Office Department (Box-folder 7:38))
  - n.d. Photograph - Samuel Meade, married to Dorothy Jones (Box-folder 7:39))
  - n.d. Photograph - Amaza Lee Meredith (Box-folder 7:40))
  - n.d. Photograph - [Jenetta Moore?] and her mother (Box-folder 7:41))
  - n.d. Photograph - [Mrs. Dan Moses] (Box-folder 7:42))
  - 1959, 1973 Photograph - Clarence Muse, actor (1889-1979) (Box-folder 7:43))
  - n.d. Photograph - Lucille Dixie Palmer (Box-folder 7:44))
  - 1908 Sep 23 Photograph - Henry N. Parker (Box-folder 7:45))
  - n.d. Photograph - Professor Ulysses S. Grant Patterson, vocalist and cornet player (1867-1916) (Box-folder 7:46))
  - n.d. Photograph - [Seymore Pearson ?] (Box-folder 7:47))
  - n.d. Photograph - James Duval Penn (Box-folder 7:48))
  - n.d. Photograph - Poetry Contest, 12 photographs taken during the Anne Spencer Poetry Contest of her garden, house, and contestants (oversize)
  - 1923-1951, n.d. Photograph - Alroy Spencer Long Rivers (Box-folder 7:49))
  - n.d. Photograph - Francis Ellis Rivers (Box-folder 7:50))
  - [1948?] Photograph - Francis Ellis Rivers and Alroy Spencer Long Wedding, Camden, New Jersey (Box-folder 7:51))
  - 1977 Feb 25 Photograph - Chuck Robb, signed and inscribed to the Friends of Anne Spencer Memorial Foundation (Box-folder 7:52))
  - n.d. Photograph - Clara Seay, wife of Dunbar High School principal (Box-folder 7:53))
  - n.d. Photograph - Lt. Sims and his wife, Minnie Hayes Sims (Box-folder 7:54))
  - n.d. Photograph - Gaylord Smith (Box-folder 7:55))
  - n.d. Photograph - Thomas [Smith?] (Box-folder 7:56))
  - 1896 Photograph - Anne Spencer, age 14 (Box-folder 8:1))
  - 1899 Photograph - Anne Spencer (Box-folder 8:2))
  - 1903 Photograph - Anne Spencer and first daughter, Bethel (Box-folder 8:3))
  - [1905] Photograph - Anne Spencer, age 23 (Box-folder 8:4))
  - 1917 Photograph - Anne Spencer (Box-folder 8:5))
  - 1931 Photograph - Anne Spencer as Librarian at Dunbar High School, Lynchburg, Virginia (Box-folder 8:6))
  - [1934] Photograph - Anne Spencer (Box-folder 8:7))
  - [ca. 1968] 8:Photograph - Anne Spencer, head shot, signed (oversize)
  - 1971 Photograph - Anne Spencer (Box-folder 8:8))
  - 1972 Photograph - Anne Spencer in her study (Box-folder 8:9))
  - [1975] Photograph - Anne Spencer, seated (7 oversize)
  - 1925, 1944-1960, n.d. Photograph - Anne Spencer in her garden, including photographs with niece, Hilda Spencer Crisp and Edward Spencer (Box-folder 8:10))
  - 1919, 1964-1978, n.d. Photograph - Anne Spencer Home in Lynchburg, Virginia, Slides of the house and interior walls showing the placement of photographs, etc.; photograph and negative showing lamp given to Anne Spencer at her wedding; painting hanging in one of the bedrooms of 1313 Pierce; two cats, "Phoebe" and "Judge" (Box-folder 8:11))
  - 1929, 1961 Photograph - Anne Spencer and Edward A. Spencer, one photograph with two granddaughters, Anne Bethel Stevenson and Barbara Ann Stevenson (Box-folder 8:12))
  - 1938, 1956, n.d. Photograph - Anne Howard Spencer and Children (Box-folder 8:13))
  - n.d. Photograph - Carrie Smith Spencer, wife of Charles Spencer and daughter of the Mayor of Lynchburg (Box-folder 8:14))
  - n.d. Photograph - Carrie Trotter Spencer, wife of Warwick Spencer, Jr. (Box-folder 8:15))
  - n.d. Photograph - Charles [Sumpter] Spencer (1873-1957) (Box-folder 8:16))
  - 1911-1983,n.d. Photograph - Chauncey Edward Spencer, including photographs with Robert L. Alexander, Mayor Robert B. Blackwell, Highland Park, Michigan, and Astronaut Lt. Colonel Guion S. Bluford (Box-folder 8:17))
  - 1939 May 16 Photograph - Chauncey Spencer and Dale L. White in Lincoln Paige Biplane, at Preston Glenn Airport, inscribed by White to Anne and Edward Spencer (Box-folder 8:18))
  - [1893?], 1910, n.d. Photograph - Edward "Alexander" Spencer (1876-1964), age [17?], and as older man (Box-folder 8:19))
  - ca. 1942-1948, n.d. Photograph - Edward A. Spencer and grandson, Edward A. Spencer II (Box-folder 8:20))
  - n.d. Photograph - Howard Nathaniel Spencer (1880-1968), Edward's brother (Box-folder 8:21))
  - n.d. Photograph - Kyle Marietta O. Spencer, granddaughter of Anne and Edward Spencer, at age 12 (Box-folder 8:22))
  - 1903, n.d Photograph - Mary Susan Payne Spencer, mother of Edward A. Spencer (Box-folder 8:23))
  - n.d. Photograph - Nelson Payne Spencer (1883-1966), "Uncle Shelly" (Box-folder 8:24))
  - n.d. Photograph - [Roger Rhodes Spencer], Carrie's son (Box-folder 8:25))
  - n.d. Photograph - Shelley Mae Spencer, daughter of Nelson Payne and Cora Meredith Spencer (Box-folder 26))
  - n.d. Photograph - Warwick Spencer, Jr. (1878-1967) (Box-folder 8:27))
  - 1891 Photograph - Spencer Family Portrait, Warwick Spencer, Sr. (1847-1927) and Mary Susan Payne Spencer (1848-1936) with children (Box-folder 8:28))
  - 1952-1965, n.d. Photograph - Spencer family snapshots (Box-folder 8:29))
  - n.d. Photograph - Barbara Stevenson ("Bobbi") (Box-folder 8:30))
  - 1923, 1934 Photograph - Bethel C. Spencer Stevenson (Box-folder 8:31))
  - n.d. Photograph - Iris Terry, childhood picture (Box-folder 8:32))
  - 1934 Dec 1-15 Photograph - Second Autumn Exhibit of Paintings by Wiley Lane Thompson and David Patterson Boyd (Box-folder 8:33))
  - n.d. Photograph - Anne Spencer Thurman (Box-folder 8:34))
  - 1975 Jul 31-Aug 2 Photograph - Tuskegee Airmen National Convention, Detroit Michigan, including: Enoch P. Waters, Jr.; Chauncey Spencer and the daughter of Grover C. Nash; and Willa P. Brown accepting the award of merit (Box-folder 8:35))
  - 1915, n.d. Photograph - Unidentified Men (Box-folder 8:36))
  - n.d. Photograph - Unidentified Women (1 of 2 folders) (Box-folder 8:37))
  - n.d. Photograph - Unidentified Women (2 of 2 folders) (Box-folder 9:1))
  - 1921 Photograph - Virginia Club Board, University of Virginia, taken from Corks and Curls, and including Murrell Edmunds and Virginius Dabney (Box-folder 9:2))
  - [post 1978] Photograph - Virginia Historic Landmarks Commission marker honoring Anne Spencer (oversize)
  - 1908, 1910 Photograph - Virginia Theological Seminary Faculty (Box-folder 9:3))
  - [1920?] Photograph - Virginia Theological Seminary and College, Lynchburg, Virginia, Building (Box-folder 9:4))
  - n.d. Photograph - [John?] White, husband of Emaline Spencer White (1871-1897), father of Gertrude and Bessie (Box-folder 9:5))
  - n.d. Photograph - Catalog created by the Friends of Anne Spencer Memorial Foundation (1 of 2 folders) (Box-folder 9:6))
  - n.d. Photograph - Catalog created by the Friends of Anne Spencer Memorial Foundation (2 of 2 folders) (Box-folder 9:7))
  - n.d. Photograph - Negative File (Box-folder 9:8))
  - n.d. Photograph - Negative File for Anne Spencer Oversize Photographs (Box-folder 9:9))
- Financial and Legal Papers and Volumes (9:10-13:4)
  - 1829 Apr 30 Financial and Legal Papers - Deed between Job Bryant Bennett and Abraham and Betsy Bennett, New Durham, Strafford County, New Hampshire (Box-folder 9:10))
  - 1910-1975 Financial and Legal Papers (Box-folder 9:11))
  - 1928, 1950-1961 Financial and Legal Papers - Property Management Business of Edward A. Spencer (Box-folder 9:12))
  - 1962-1975 Financial and Legal Papers - Property Management Business of Edward A. Spencer and Family (Box-folder 9:13))
  - 1955-1967 Financial and Legal Papers - Property Management Business of Edward A. Spencer - Statements (Box-folder 9:14))
  - 1961-1963 Financial and Legal Papers - Tax Return Business of Edward A. Spencer (Box-folder 10:1))
  - 1961-1975 Financial and Legal Papers - Wills of Anne B. Spencer and Edward A. Spencer, and Estate Papers of Anne Spencer (Box-folder 10:2))
  - 1904-1911 Ledger of Edward Spencer (Box-folder 10:3))
  - 1907-1910 Ledger of Edward Spencer (Box-folder 10:4))
  - 1911-1917 Ledger of Edward Spencer (Box-folder 10:5))
  - 1917-1963 Ledger of Edward Spencer, including wood account and improvements to rental properties (Box-folder 10:6))
  - 1935-1941 Ledger of Edward Spencer, with index (Box-folder 10:7))
  - 1954-1961 Ledger of Edward Spencer [Account Book] (Box-folder 11:1))
  - 1963-1964 Ledger of Edward Spencer, includes some writings of Anne Spencer which have been copied and placed in the Manuscript Series (Box-folder 11:2))
  - 1942-1950 Ledger of Edward Spencer No. 1, with index, and section on costs of improvements to his rental properties (Box-folder 11:3))
  - 1955-1963, 1970 Ledger of Edward Spencer No. 3, with index of "accounts" and "tenants," and writings of Anne Spencer on the endpapers of the ledger, including: (front of ledger) moderns quoting Emerson; the search for truth; references to "the 13 th fairy," Poe's "take your beak from out my heart," Keziah Dyke; jailkeeper Tyree and Big Boy Davis; Agnew; Mrs. Stowe (Uncle Tom) vs Joel Chandler Harris (Uncle Remus); draft of a poem dated April 25, 1970; (back of ledger), references to experience; 10 black kittens; Birmingham; porter-conductor; Jim Crow Library; "Terence McSwiney" Charles Lindbergh; Tony, Emmy, and Oscar Awards; "Moon 14," and "How Far North Did Abraham Lincoln Go - in Space or History?" (Box-folder 11:4))
  - 1941 Ledger of Chicken Business, with index (Box-folder 11:5))
  - 1952-1955 Ledger of Edward Spencer's Tax Business, with index (Box-folder 11:6))
  - 1957-1959 Ledger of Edward Spencer's Tax Business, with index (Box-folder 11:7))
  - 1962-1963, 1972 Ledger of Edward Spencer's Tax Business, and includes writings of Anne Spencer, which have been copied and placed in the Manuscript Series (Box-folder 11:8))
  - 1960-1972 Ledger of Edward Spencer's Tax Business, with index, and includes writings of Anne Spencer: (front of ledger and index section) references to Matthew Arnold's "Darkling Plain," small town v the city, and television; "People"; musings about her mother on her "106 th birthday"; "My Generals"; manuscript beginning "The storm rising and falling in my soul by day, by night" (October 1972); and in the back of the ledger, beginning on page 120), manuscript beginning "Being so epitomized"; manuscript beginning "They come the vagrant ones" page 124 (October 1970); manuscript beginning "I am the only one left who remembers Gregory Hayes" page 126; "The Advisor" (December 1970) on page 127; manuscript beginning "[For?] I know God is. But pleasure is not" discussing kids and education on pages 128-129; discussion of bawdiness, the Jews and begot, Americanization of sex, and Stefan Lorant on page 132; draft to Mr. Ferrone about who could write a preface for her work on pages 133-134; and manuscript about Abraham Lincoln on back endpaper (Box-folder 12:1))
  - 1957-1964 Notarial Record Book of Edward Spencer, with index (Box-folder 12:2))
  - 1931-1933 Receipt Book of Edward Spencer (Box-folder 12:3))
  - 1933-1934 Receipt Book of Edward Spencer (Box-folder 12:4))
  - 1934-1938 Receipt Book of Edward Spencer (Box-folder 12:5))
  - 1938-1942 Receipt Book of Edward Spencer (Box-folder 12:6))
  - 1943-1948 Receipt Book of Edward Spencer (Box-folder 12:7))
  - 1948-1951 Receipt Book of Edward Spencer (Box-folder 13:1))
  - 1951-1953 Receipt Book of Edward Spencer (Box-folder 13:2))
  - 1954-1964 Receipt Book of Edward Spencer (Box-folder 13:3))
  - 1970, n.d. Steno Notebook concerning legal cases, mostly blank (Box-folder 13:4))
- Topical and Miscellaneous Files (13:5-17:6)
  - 1964, n.d. Addresses (Box-folder 13:5))
  - 1977-1991 Anne Spencer House - Thank You Letters (Box-folder 13:6))
  - 1976 Jan-1977 Feb Anne Spencer House - Virginia Landmarks Register Materials (Box-folder 13:7))
  - 1996-2007 Anne Spencer Poetry Contest (Box-folder 13:8))
  - 1959, 1977, 1998, n.d. Biographical Information (Box-folder 13:9))
  - 1941 Dec Blueprint for a Hanger at the Advanced Single Engine Flying School, Dothan, Alabama, and the Air Corp Advanced Flying School, Tuskegee, Alabama (oversize)
  - n.d. Broadside Facsimiles concerning slavery, African-Americans, the Civil War, formerly tacked upon the walls of Anne Spencer's study (Box-folder 13:10))
  - n.d. Broadside Facsimiles (some courtesy of Pioneer Historical Society) concerning slavery (4), reward for murderers of Abraham Lincoln, dissolution of the Union, Gettysburg Address, and a letter from Grant to Lee, formerly tacked upon the walls of Anne Spencer's study (oversize)
  - n.d. Broadside Facsimiles (some courtesy of Pioneer Historical Society) concerning the election of Lincoln, a playbill for Ford Theater, mourning for Lincoln, and slavery, which were formerly tacked upon the walls of Anne Spencer's study (oversize)
  - 1947-1977 Business and Calling Cards, with some admittance tickets to events (Box-folder 13:11))
  - 1943-1977 Civil Rights and Related Papers (Box-folder 14:1))
  - 1937 Jun 17 "Criterion" Certificate stating "The grand United Standard name of the Black race and her descendent is (Criterion)" signed by B[althus] Millionaire Watkins (oversize)
  - 1933-1966 Dunbar High School, Lynchburg, Virginia (Box-folder 14:2))
  - n.d. Dust Jackets for anthologies containing Spencer poems (Box-folder 14:3))
  - 1986 "Edankrall" Print, Lynchburg Bicentennial Card Honoring Anne Spencer (Box-folder 14:4))
  - 1929-1971 Education, chiefly statements sent by Lynchburg, Virginia School Board and South Carolina State College (Box-folder 14:5))
  - [1866?] Engravings from The American Conflict A History of the Great Rebellion in the United States of America, 1860-1865 by Horace Greeley (Box-folder 14:6))
  - 1976 The Friends of the Anne Spencer Memorial Foundation (Box-folder 14:7))
  - 1977 The Friends of the Anne Spencer Memorial Foundation (Box-folder 14:8))
  - 1979-1997 The Friends of the Anne Spencer Memorial Foundation (Box-folder 14:9))
  - [1999?] The Friends of the Anne Spencer Memorial Foundation - Notes and Photocopies of the Museum Photograph Archive (Box-folder 14:10))
  - 1931-1999 Garden (Box-folder 14:11))
  - 1989 Oct 15 Guest Book for Presentation Ceremony Virginia General Assembly Resolution honoring Anne Scales Spencer (Box-folder 14:12))
  - 1974 "Introduction" by William T. Whitsitt to the autobiography Who Is Chauncey Spencer? (Box-folder 14:13))
  - 1920-1949 Invitations (Box-folder 15:1))
  - 1950-1954 Invitations (Box-folder 15:2))
  - 1955-1959 Invitations (Box-folder 15:3))
  - 1960-1963 Invitations (Box-folder 15:4))
  - 1964-1969 Invitations (Box-folder 15:5))
  - 1970-1977 Invitations (Box-folder 15:6))
  - n.d. Invitations (Box-folder 15:7))
  - 1951-1974 Invitations (Box-folder 15:8))
  - 1970 Key to Cardinal City given to Chauncey Spencer (oversize)
  - 1935-1975 Memberships (Box-folder 15:9))
  - 1944-1971, n.d. Memorabilia (Box-folder 15:10))
  - 1959, 1964, n.d. Miscellaneous Materials, including: Community Funeral Home Visitors Register for unidentified person; a pamphlet of "testimonial letters" written by Laurence Foster, Ph.D. on behalf of W.H.R. Powell; advertisement from the editors of the 7 Poets Press for Charles Bukowski's Longshot Poems for Broke Players; a modern typed copy (1959) of the will of William Gough, dated January 16, 1863; a Prospectus "Operation Bootstrap"; "The World and U.S." presented by Graduate Faculties Alumni of Columbia University (1964); and Japanese Short Verse-Forms sheet (Box-folder 15:11))
  - 1932 "A Miscellany Selections from Work done by the students in the course of Creative Literature at Fisk University" (Box-folder 15:12))
  - 1864-1965 News clippings and Printed (Box-folder 15:13))
  - 1966-1998, n.d. News clippings and Printed (Box-folder 15:14))
  - 1922-2000 News clippings and Printed - Anne Spencer (Box-folder 15:15))
  - 1948-1977, n.d. News clippings and Printed - Spencer Family (Box-folder 16:1))
  - 1953 May 18 News clipping "W-P [Wright Patterson] Man Helped Break Race Barriers" in AMC World concerning Chauncey Spencer (oversize)
  - 1918-1975 Obituaries and Eulogies (Box-folder 16:2))
  - 1939-2004 Papers concerning Chauncey Spencer (Box-folder 16:3))
  - 1896-1966 Papers concerning the Spencer and Related Families (Box-folder 16:4))
  - 1927-1976 Permissions and Publication Agreements (Box-folder 16:5))
  - n.d. Poetry and Manuscripts by Others, including: [Robert Browning]; Murrell Edmunds; Ethel Watts Munford; and M. Helen Vickers (Box-folder 16:6))
  - 1964 Poetry by Gerald William Barrax, Mimeograph copies (Box-folder 16:7))
  - 1940-1975 Political and Campaign Papers (Box-folder 16:8))
  - 1923-1956 Programs, (1 of 2 folders) (Box-folder 16:9))
  - 1957-2006 Programs, (2 of 2 folders) (Box-folder 16:10))
  - ca. 1924 Reference Questions Notebook from Dunbar Library (Box-folder 16:11))
  - 1925-1960 Reviews (Box-folder 17:1))
  - [1999 Feb 5] "Searching for Anne Spencer" by Pat Doyle, Rough Draft, with notes (Box-folder 17:2))
  - n.d. Selected Bibliography for Anne Spencer (Box-folder 17:3))
  - 1942, n.d. Stationery and Christmas Cards (Blank) of Anne Spencer (Box-folder 17:4))
  - 1971 Talks by Garnell Stamps (Box-folder 17:5))
  - 1939-2001 Tuskegee Airmen (Box-folder 17:6))
  - [1968 Aug 8] 30th Wedding Anniversary Congratulation card from President and Mrs. Johnson mounted on a wooden plaque (oversize)
  - [1991?] 50th Wedding Anniversary "card" wood-burned on a block of wood and mailed from Chauncey Spencer to his wife, Anne Spencer (oversize)
- Manuscripts and Poems (Box-folder 17:7-22:55)
  - Manuscripts with a title (17:7-17:61)
    - 1948, 1972 Manuscript Articles written by Anne Spencer, for possible publication as a weekly column "The Indicator" for The Pittsburgh Courier but not used according to the accompanying explanatory letter from her son, Chauncey Spencer, June 25, 1972, to Lee Greene (Box-folder 17:7))
    - 1956 Nov Manuscript Autobiographical Piece by Anne Spencer [Untitled], copy sent to Lee Greene in 1976 (Box-folder 17:8))
    - n.d. Manuscript "Bastion at Newark" (Box-folder 17:9))
    - n.d. Manuscript "Being 14" (Box-folder 17:10))
    - [post 1962-1963] Manuscript "Books," chiefly discussing fairy tales (Box-folder 17:11))
    - n.d. Manuscript "Books: Chattel Slavery or Why I Dislike Booker T." (Box-folder 17:12))
    - n.d. Manuscript "The Chieftains" (Box-folder 17:13))
    - n.d. Manuscript "Cousin Lou" (Box-folder 17:14))
    - n.d. Manuscript "A Dedication" (Box-folder 17:15))
    - n.d. Manuscript "Finale" (Box-folder 17:16))
    - n.d. Manuscripts "For Madison Avenue" and "Fuzzy Wozzie" (Box-folder 17:17))
    - n.d. Manuscript "For Narcissus" (Box-folder 17:18))
    - [post 1962] Manuscript "For These Last Will-Testamentary Pieces" (Box-folder 17:19))
    - n.d. Manuscript "For Unbalance" (Box-folder 17:20))
    - n.d. Manuscript "Fun Is Always Funny" (Box-folder 17:21))
    - [1961?] Manuscripts "G.A. Albany '61 Frank McGee" and "Interimposition" on back of sheet (Box-folder 17:22))
    - 1972 Feb 6 Manuscript "The Garden," in the format of a letter to "Dear Lee" [Greene] (Box-folder 17:23))
    - n.d. Manuscript "Generals" (Box-folder 17:24))
    - n.d. Manuscript "Harpers Ferry" (Box-folder 17:25))
    - n.d. Manuscript "Hills of Placidity" (Box-folder 17:26))
    - ca. 1924 Manuscript "In the Thicket" possibly a draft of Spencer's analysis of a short story by James Weldon Johnson which appeared in The Dial (see Greene pages 61-62) (Box-folder 17:27))
    - [post 1968 Sep] Manuscript "Land of the Free" (Box-folder 17:28))
    - [post 1964] Manuscript "The Lear Lady" (Box-folder 17:29))
    - 1968 Feb 14, n.d. Manuscript "Le Roi Meets Lincoln" or "When Abraham Lincoln Met Leroy Jones" (Box-folder 17:30))
    - n.d. Manuscript "Le Roi Jones" (Box-folder 17:31))
    - n.d. Manuscript "Love and Gardens" (Box-folder 17:32))
    - n.d. Manuscript "Miss Hallee" (Box-folder 17:33))
    - n.d. Manuscript "Modern Poetry" (Box-folder 17:34))
    - [post 1960 Dec] Manuscript "Mortal Sin is not Unbelief" (Box-folder 17:35))
    - 1945 Feb 3 Manuscript "Mother Comes to Defense of Patterson Fields' Chauncey Spencer" Letter to the Editor of The Ohio State News typescript copy (Box-folder 17:36))
    - n.d. Manuscript "Nature" two apparently unrelated manuscripts with the same title (Box-folder 17:37))
    - 1970 Manuscript "Notes on Lindbergh" (Box-folder 17:38))
    - n.d. Manuscript "On Second Thought" (Box-folder 17:39))
    - n.d. Manuscript "On Swahili" (Box-folder 17:40))
    - n.d. Manuscript "Over the Ocean Waves" (Box-folder 17:41))
    - n.d. Manuscript "The Paladin" (Box-folder 17:42))
    - n.d. Manuscript "Passover" or "Darkling Plain" titles presumed to belong to the page following them in the ledger (Box-folder 17:43))
    - n.d. Manuscript Polish adage written in a calligraphic hand on a large poster board, "The first place for me to look for a helping hand is at the dangle end of my own arm." (oversize)
    - [1972 Apr] Manuscript "Preface to Lee's Collection Dear Children" with a typed transcript by Lee Greene (Box-folder 17:44))
    - n.d. Manuscript "Premonitions"; also includes other manuscripts on the same sheet, beginning "compromise is accepting a little of what you know to be wrong," "I know why the sea beats her breast in the dark," and "The martins have come" (Box-folder 17:45))
    - n.d. Manuscript "Rose Beetles" (Box-folder 17:46))
    - n.d. Manuscript "Sammy" (Box-folder 17:47))
    - n.d. Manuscript "Sociology of the Hebrew Religion" (Box-folder 17:48))
    - n.d. Manuscript "Some Literary People and the Negro" (Box-folder 17:49))
    - n.d. Manuscript "Speaking of Rivers" (Box-folder 17:50))
    - n.d. Manuscript "The State Legislature Survey on Education" (Box-folder 17:51))
    - n.d. Manuscript "Sunday at the Prison" (Box-folder 17:52))
    - n.d. Manuscript "Sybarite" (Box-folder 17:53))
    - n.d. Manuscript "13 th Fairy" (Box-folder 17:54))
    - [post 1964 Feb] Manuscript "Time Machine" (Box-folder 17:55))
    - n.d. Manuscript "Tyke" (Box-folder 17:56))
    - n.d. Manuscript "Unfinished Business or War on the Third Front" (Box-folder 17:57))
    - n.d. Manuscript "Virginia as Narcissus" with a note (Box-folder 17:58))
    - n.d. Manuscript "The Web" quoting her mother about slavery (Box-folder 17:59))
    - n.d. Manuscript "Why Read Books?" also includes a paragraph about writing about Jesus, a draft paragraphs written to a Mr. Kerlin about accepting some things on faith, a few lines about orphan Mary, deaf and dumb, and a statement about a library (Box-folder 17:60))
    - n.d. Manuscript "Windows" (Box-folder 17:61))
  - Manuscripts arranged by beginning line (Box-folder 18:1-18:39)
    - n.d. Manuscript beginning "Books are not just books" (Box-folder 18:1))
    - n.d. Manuscript beginning "Evening and Morning the Sixth Day" (Box-folder 18:2))
    - n.d. Manuscript beginning "For not every white in the South struck Negroes or struck oil" (Box-folder 18:3))
    - n.d. Manuscript beginning "He fled from the very thought of it while new stars blazed" (Box-folder 18:4))
    - n.d. Manuscripts beginning "A husband can more easily suit other women" and "Ophelia's parents were old when she was born" (Box-folder 18:5))
    - [post 1951] Manuscript beginning "If one must admit to degrees of nobility" (Box-folder 18:6))
    - [1970] Manuscript beginning "If typewriters have souls most are in for a long fall - come Judgment Day" (Box-folder 18:7))
    - n.d. Manuscript beginning "I'm the one against the contorted men" (Box-folder 18:8))
    - n.d. Manuscript beginning "Invisible is our touchless earth" (Box-folder 18:9))
    - n.d. Manuscript beginning "It's no doubt somewhat physiologically true, that from the moment one is born" (Box-folder 18:10))